A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Latin America and the Caribbean, Andean Region and the Southern Cone, Program Staff Files FA649
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Latin America and the Caribbean, Andean Region and the Southern Cone, Program Staff Files
1989-1991
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA649
1.2 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Program Staff Files, 1989-1991; I
  - Amazon Meeting, Belem, Paraguay (July 23-August 4, 1990) -- Meeting Planning Materials and Reports (Box 1)
  - Christine Pendzich -- International Affairs Grants and Proposal Evaluations, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean Reports Re: Environment and Development, Drug Trafficking, Latin American Visits, and Regional Meetings, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Lima Office Regional Meeting -- Notes, Report, Apr 4, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Human Rights -- Reports, Memoranda, Project Evaluations, 1990
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted from scholarly access.
  - Human Rights -- "Enhancing Human Rights in Hispanic South America: Retrospect and Prospect" by Tom Farer, Dec 15, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Michael Shifter -- Stanford University Workshop Re: Democratic Transition in Latin America, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health -- Program Officers' Meeting, Tarrytown, NY (December 6-8, 1990) -- Planning Materials, Notes, Reports, Dec 6-8, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Governance (folder 1), 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Governance (folder 2), 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- International Affairs, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Lima Administration Incl. Report Re: Lima Office Termination, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Lima -- Biennial Budget, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Lima -- Budget, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Lima -- Office Future and Establishment of Santiago Office, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Poverty Program, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Public Policy Initiative, Incl. Visit to Mexico (January 8-10, 1990) (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- Budget, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- Cost Study, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- General, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- Legal Status, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- Logistics, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- Newspaper Article ("La Segunda") Re: Ford Foundation Return to Chile, Mar 15, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- Setup, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Santiago Office -- Staffing, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- Sustainable Development, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Offenheiser (RO) -- United Nations Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED) -- Planning Materials for 1992 Conference, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Financial ledger - Lima, Peru Office, 1971 April - 1977 December; 16x22 box. (Box 2)
    File Plan
    Former box ID 16976.
  - Financial ledger - Lima, Peru Office, 1977 December - 1981 April; 16x22 box. (Box 2)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1989-1991
  - Berman, Peter; Health Economics, Health Financing, and Health Needs of Poor Women, Children in India, Oct 1990 (Report #019899)
  - Farer, Tom; Enhancing Human Rights in Hispanic South America -- Retrospective and Prospect, Sep 15, 1989 (Report #019897)
  - Offenheiser, Raymond; Termination Report -- The Lima Office, Jan 31, 1991 (Report #019900)
  - Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 Biennial Budget, Lima -- April 1989 Program Reviews (Report #019901)
  - Reproductive Health and Population -- A Foundation Strategy for the 1990s (Report #019898)